[
    {
        "question": "The epigraph in Chapter One comments on the difficulty of distinguishing between",
        "a": "peace and conflict",
        "b": "dreams and reality",
        "c": "activity and passivity",
        "d": "utopia and dystopia",
        "e": "good and evil",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements does NOT describe Taoism’s influence on Le Guin?",
        "a": "She created characters like George Orr who possessed the Taoist quality of wholeness.",
        "b": "She focused on the Taoist concept of utopia in many of her works.",
        "c": "She included quotes from Taoist philosophers in The Lathe of Heaven.",
        "d": "She rewrote a classic Taoist text.",
        "e": "She wrote scenes featuring disagreements between Eastern and Western viewpoints.",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who wrote, 'Those whom heaven helps we call the sons of heaven'?",
        "a": "Sun Tzu",
        "b": "Xun Kuang",
        "c": "Lao Tzu",
        "d": "Confucius",
        "e": "Zhuangzi",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which character is the 'lathe' of Chapter Three’s epigraph?",
        "a": "Heather Lelache",
        "b": "E’nememen Asfah",
        "c": "Tiua’k Ennbe Ennbe",
        "d": "William Haber",
        "e": "George Orr",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "How did Victor Hugo’s writing influence The Lathe of Heaven?",
        "a": "Orr and Haber have discussions about Hugo’s works.",
        "b": "Hugo’s writing inspired Le Guin to explore the concept of utopia.",
        "c": "Le Guin includes a quote from Hugo as an epigraph.",
        "d": "Orr’s outlook on life is heavily inspired by Hugo’s beliefs.",
        "e": "Haber’s outlook on life is heavily inspired by Hugo’s beliefs.",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which science fiction text serves as the inspiration for the epigraph in Chapter Four?",
        "a": "The Time Machine",
        "b": "Symzonia: A Voyage of Discovery",
        "c": "Frankenstein",
        "d": "A Modern Utopia",
        "e": "Fahrenheit 451",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Le Guin’s most famous short story is titled",
        "a": "“The Birthmark”",
        "b": "“The Ones Who Walk Away from Omelas”",
        "c": "“Bartleby the Scrivener”",
        "d": "“The Unparalleled Adventure of One Hans Pfaall”",
        "e": "“There Will Come Soft Rains”",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Several of Le Guin’s novels and short stories explored the concept of",
        "a": "space exploration",
        "b": "alternate histories",
        "c": "apocalypse",
        "d": "the infernal machine",
        "e": "utopia",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who wrote that '[m]odern SF has gone beyond this irreconcilable Utopian/Dystopian conflict'?",
        "a": "Ray Bradbury",
        "b": "Samuel Delany",
        "c": "Mary Shelley",
        "d": "H. G. Wells",
        "e": "John Cleeve Symmes",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "How did utilitarianism influence Le Guin’s career?",
        "a": "She created characters like William Haber who subscribed to utilitarian viewpoints.",
        "b": "She included several quotes from utilitarian philosophers in The Lathe of Heaven.",
        "c": "She wrote novels like The Dispossessed that championed utilitarianism.",
        "d": "She advocated for government policies rooted in utilitarianism.",
        "e": "She intended for The Lathe of Heaven to serve as a utilitarian thought experiment.",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following philosophies shares the MOST similarities with utilitarianism?",
        "a": "deontology",
        "b": "empiricism",
        "c": "existentialism",
        "d": "consequentialism",
        "e": "rationalism",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements BEST describes Haber’s outlook on mankind’s existence?",
        "a": "Progress is futile because a utopian society is unachievable.",
        "b": "Throughout our lives, we are always spiraling toward entropy.",
        "c": "Our existence is all about change and progress.",
        "d": "Life is nothing more than waiting for death.",
        "e": "Reality is indistinguishable from dreams.",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Haber declares that he is 'pro-",
        "a": "technology",
        "b": "humanity",
        "c": "science",
        "d": "progress",
        "e": "life",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which famous building inspired the design of the foyer of Haber’s office?",
        "a": "the Hagia Sophia",
        "b": "the Colosseum",
        "c": "the Pantheon",
        "d": "the Alhambra",
        "e": "the Parthenon",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "The foyer of Haber’s office features an inscription of the quote",
        "a": "“The portal of God is non-existence.”",
        "b": "“Regard this society. You say it’s good, but I say it’s bad.”",
        "c": "“The proper study of mankind is man.”",
        "d": "“Confucius and you are both dreams, and I who say you are dreams am a dream myself.”",
        "e": "“To let understanding stop at what cannot be understood is a high attainment.”",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does Render use technology in Roger Zelazny's He Who Shapes?",
        "a": "to hypnotize people in their dreams",
        "b": "to stop people from dreaming",
        "c": "to make people fall asleep",
        "d": "to change dreams into reality",
        "e": "to shape and share dreams",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following magazines published Ursula K. Le Guin's The Lathe of Heaven?",
        "a": "Astonishing Stories",
        "b": "Amazing Stories",
        "c": "Amazing Science Fiction",
        "d": "Weird Tales",
        "e": "Asimov's Science Fiction",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following companies published the novel version of The Lathe of Heaven?",
        "a": "Charles Scribner’s Sons",
        "b": "HarperCollins",
        "c": "Simon & Schuster",
        "d": "Graywolf Press",
        "e": "W. W. Norton",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 1980 film version of The Lathe of Heaven aired on",
        "a": "NBC",
        "b": "PBS",
        "c": "CBS",
        "d": "A&E",
        "e": "ABC",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who helped direct the 1980 film version of The Lathe of Heaven?",
        "a": "David Loxton",
        "b": "Gus Van Sant",
        "c": "Ron Howard",
        "d": "Roger Swaybill",
        "e": "Alan Sharpe",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the creation of the 1980 film version of The Lathe of Heaven, Ursula Le Guin did NOT help with",
        "a": "directing",
        "b": "planning",
        "c": "casting",
        "d": "a cameo",
        "e": "rewriting",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who played Dr. William Haber in the 1980 film version of The Lathe of Heaven?",
        "a": "Lukas Haas",
        "b": "James Caan",
        "c": "Rick Moranis",
        "d": "Bruce Davidson",
        "e": "Kevin Conway",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "The architecture shown in the 1980 film version of The Lathe of Heaven is BEST described as",
        "a": "Victorian",
        "b": "Gothic",
        "c": "Modernist",
        "d": "Georgian",
        "e": "Postmodernist",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following magazines named the 1980 film version of The Lathe of Heaven one of the top one hundred greatest works of science fiction?",
        "a": "Wired",
        "b": "Time",
        "c": "Vanity Fair",
        "d": "People",
        "e": "Entertainment Weekly",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who conducted an interview with Ursula K. Le Guin for the 2000 release of the film The Lathe of Heaven?",
        "a": "Ted Turner",
        "b": "Robert C. Maynard",
        "c": "Tina Brown",
        "d": "Barbara Walters",
        "e": "Bill Moyers",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following television networks remade the film version of The Lathe of Heaven in 2002?",
        "a": "A&E",
        "b": "PBS",
        "c": "NBC",
        "d": "ABC",
        "e": "CBS",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 2002 remake of The Lathe of Heaven received a nomination for a(n)",
        "a": "Saturn Award",
        "b": "Iris Award",
        "c": "Writer’s Guild Award",
        "d": "TCA award",
        "e": "Emmy Award",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following actors played George Orr in the 2002 remake of The Lathe of Heaven?",
        "a": "Bruce Davidson",
        "b": "Kevin Conway",
        "c": "Lukas Haas",
        "d": "James Caan",
        "e": "Michael Vartan",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 2002 film version of The Lathe of Heaven did NOT",
        "a": "pay minimal attention to race or racism",
        "b": "remove the augmentor machine",
        "c": "ignore the novel’s philosophical foundation",
        "d": "remove alien characters",
        "e": "discard large portions of the plot",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ursula Le Guin found the 2002 remake of The Lathe of Heaven to be",
        "a": "disappointing",
        "b": "innovative",
        "c": "low-budget",
        "d": "inspirational",
        "e": "mediocre",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    }
]

